Kevin Doh

San Jose, CA 95138

Phone: 408-960-5481 | Email: kdoh52@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/kdoh/ | GitHub: https://github.com/kdoh52

Portfolio: https://kdoh52.github.io/

Summary

Full Stack Web Developer employing UI/UX design experience to build efficient and intuitive web applications. Effectively combines technical and creative skills to develop solutions both visual and practical. Thrives in a collaborative environment using detailed communication and attentiveness of outside perspectives.

Technical Skills

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Express, SQL, Handlebars, Python

Frameworks/Libraries: Node.js, React, MongoDB, Mongoose, APIs, jQuery, AJAX, JSON, Bootstrap,

Material-UI

Applications: Visual Studio Code, GitHub, MySQL, Adobe Creative Suite

Projects

The Coder's Corner | Repository: https://the-coders-corner | Application: https://the-coders-corner.herokuapp.com/

- Social media website geared towards helping web developers network, learn, and collaborate.
- Implemented newsfeed and chat pages. Assisted in user authentication, back-end routing, APIs, database management, and general debugging
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, Axios, Bcryptjs, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, Passport, Socket.io, Validator, React, React-Router-Dom, Material-UI, Heroku

Google Books Search | Repository: https://github.com/kdoh52/google-books-search | Application: https://afternoon-hamlet-63363.herokuapp.com/

- Website that allows a user to search the Google Books API and save/remove books from their collection.
- Implemented search bar to query the API and display results using react components. Connected MongoDB database to allow for book information to be stored in a separate tab.
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, Axios, React, React-Router-Dom, Material-UI, Heroku

Fitness Tracker | Repository: https://github.com/kdoh52/fitness-tracker | Application: https://lit-taiga-57650.herokuapp.com/

- Fitness tracker that allows a user to save workouts and view their progress graphically
- Connected front-end application to MongoDB database for inputting workouts and retrieving past data.
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, Express, Compression, MongoDB, Mongoose, Morgan, Bootstrap, Chart.js, Heroku

Experience

Student Graphic Designer (Oct 2019 - Aug 2020) UC Davis Global Affairs — Davis, CA

- Designed and edited graphics for 2018-19 Annual Report to highlight organization accomplishments and statistics.
- Developed visual solutions for over 70 projects given constraints and specifications provided by project coordinators.
- Consistently balanced 5-10 unique projects simultaneously
- Collaborated with upper-level management and other designers on a regular basis.

Social Media / Design Intern (Apr 2019 - Sep 2019)

Davis Sensory Institute — Davis, CA

- Redesigned and maintained company website on a new platform to improve user experience and functionality.
- Designed book cover for president's 400-page research publication.
- Assisted in conducting sensory research for over 100 participants.

Artistic Advisor (Oct 2018 - May 2019)

SoNE1 — Davis, CA

- Co-managed team practices of over 25 people.
- Collaborated with members in developing choreographies.
- Designed graphics for promotional material on social media and public screen display.
- Mixed audio and edited videos for YouTube channel with over 250,000 subscribers.

Education

Coding Bootcamp Certificate: Full Stack Web Development University of California, Davis Jun 2020 - Dec 2020

Bachelor of Arts (BA): UI/UX Design University of California, Davis Sept 2017 - Dec 2020

Student Graphic Designer (Oct 2019 - Aug 2020)

UC Davis Global Affairs — Davis, CA

- Designed and edited graphics for promotional materials including posters, web pages, flyers, etc.
- Created visual solutions given constraints and specifications from project coordinators.
- Collaborated with management and other designers on a regular basis.

Social Media / Design Intern (Apr 2019 - Sep 2019)

Davis Sensory Institute — Davis, CA

- Redesigned and maintained company website.
- Designed graphics for various publications.
- Assisted in conducting sensory research.

Artistic Advisor (Oct 2018 - May 2019)

SoNE1 — Davis, CA

- Co-managed team practices.
- Collaborated with members in developing pieces.
- Designed graphics for social media.
- Mixed audio and edited videos for YouTube channel with over 250,000 subscribers.